Cuneiform Tablet Collection
Cuneiform Tablet Collection
2100-2000 BCE
489 items
Sumerian clay tablets from the Ur III period with cuneiform script of economic content from the cities of Umma, Drehem and Lagash.
4806012
Biographical History
The Syracuse cuneiform tablets are of Sumerian origin and were created during the Ur III period (2100-2000 BCE). The Sumerian city state culture was the first of the early civilizations of the fertile crescent and flourished in what is today southern Iraq from the 4th millennium to the end of the 3rd millennium with a short interlude (Akkadian and Gutian period) in the 23rd and 22nd century BCE. The Sumerians are generally credited with the invention of the cuneiform script which in itself represents the earliest known writing system. It is named after the 'wedge'-shaped imprints of a reed stylus by which scribes encoded their language on a clay surface. Cuneiform writing can be traced back to around 3000 BCE; the Syracuse cuneiform tablets were created during the short Sumerian Renaissance at the end of the 3rd century BCE. Most of them seem to have originated in the city of Umma, some come from Drehem, a cattle market, and a few were created at the city of Lagash.
[This account relies on: Sigrist, Marcel, "The Cuneiform Tablets at Syracuse University." The Courier 17.2 and 17.3 (1980): 3-23.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Syracuse University's Cuneiform Tablet Collection consists - as does the great majority of cuneiform tablets in general - of accounting records of largely economic nature. "The Umma tablets deal mainly with the workers [...] needed to excavate and clean the canals, to work in the fields, and to harvest barley. Another group deals with the treatment of hides to make leather objects. Several, of which the longest forecasts the date harvest, come from various date farmers. After the projections about production, the scribe made the necessary corrections after the harvest." (Sigrist, 1980, p. 18)
All dates given in the inventory are BCE.
Other Formats Available
Digitized images of the Syracuse cuneiform tablets are available via the Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative (CDLI). To limit the search results to the Syracuse collection in the CDLI, click on "Full Search" and enter "Syracuse" in the "Collection" field in the "Collection Information" section; this will bring up all 489 images of our tablets. Please note (as stated in Arrangement of the Collection ) that the images in the CDLI use the identification numbers assigned in Marcel Sigrist's publication.
Arrangement of the Collection
The tablets remain in original order. Please note that Syracuse University's numbering of the tablets was done before Marcel Sigrist's publication Textes économiques néo-sumériens de l'Université de Syracuse, Paris: Editions Recherche sur les Civilisations, 1983. In his publication, Sigrist proposes a different order which has been followed by the Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative (CDLI). This finding aid follows the original order of Syracuse University's Cuneiform Tablet Collection but gives the corresponding number of the CDLI's (= Sigrist's) arrangement in parentheses.
Related Material
See also Marcel Sigrist's article "The Cuneiform Tablets at Syracuse University," available through Surface, our institutional repository.
Subject and Genre Headings
Civilization, ancient.; Sumerian language -- Texts.; Mesopotamian civilizations.; Umma (Extinct city); Drehem (Extinct city); Lagash (Extinct city); Clay.; Tablets (information artifacts)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Gloves must be worn when working with tablets. Specific tablets are restricted (as noted in individual boxes).
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1910
Inventory
- Cuneiform tablets
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 1 (CDLI 476), circa 2100-2000; levy of cattle (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 2 (CDLI 477), circa 2100-2000; delivery of wooden objects (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 3 (CDLI 478), circa 2100-2000; delivery of sheep (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 4 (CDLI 479), circa 2100-2000; land of different domains (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 5 (CDLI 480), circa 2100-2000; levy of livestock (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 6 (CDLI 481), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 7 (CDLI 482), circa 2100-2000; letter (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 8 (CDLI 483), circa 2100-2000; delivery of products for the treatment of leather (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 9 (CDLI 484), circa 2100-2000; arrears of sheep deliveries (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 10 (CDLI 485), circa 2100-2000; workers for field work (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 11 (CDLI 486), circa 2100-2000; receipt for a product? (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 12 (CDLI 487), circa 2100-2000; delivery of hides such as sattukku (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 13 (CDLI 488), circa 2100-2000; receipt for cattle (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 14 (CDLI 489), circa 2100-2000; levy of leather objects (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 15 (CDLI 64), circa 2100-2000; delivery of sheep (Box 1)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 16 (CDLI 58), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation works (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 17 (CDLI 93), circa 2100-2000; delivery of a hide (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 18 (CDLI 391), circa 2100-2000; account of barley bills (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 19 (CDLI 29), circa 2100-2000; women overseeing a reservoir (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 20 (CDLI 113), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation work (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 21 (CDLI 114), circa 2100-2000; workers for the threshing of barley (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 22 (CDLI 234), circa 2100-2000; workers working on marsa (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 23 (CDLI 305), circa 2100-2000; delivery of bread (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 24 (CDLI 102), circa 2100-2000; workers for carrying reeds (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 25 (CDLI 40), circa 2100-2000; receipt for leather bags ? (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 26 (CDLI 53), circa 2100-2000; workers for digging furrows on two fields (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 27 (CDLI 276), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation and field work (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 28 (CDLI 294), circa 2100-2000; workers loading a flour boat (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 29 (CDLI 31), circa 2100-2000; woman hired (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 30 (CDLI 65), circa 2100-2000; workers for the transport of the barley (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 31 (CDLI 239), circa 2100-2000; women overseeing a basin (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 32 (CDLI 204), circa 2100-2000; management of livestock (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 33 (CDLI 97), circa 2100-2000; receipt for sickles (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 34 (CDLI 265), circa 2100-2000; delivery of reed baskets (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 35 (CDLI 216), circa 2100-2000; receipt for leather bags (Box 2)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 36 (CDLI 206), circa 2100-2000; receipt for hides (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 37 (CDLI 177), circa 2100-2000; receipt for leather (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 38 (CDLI 292), circa 2100-2000; delivery of containers (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 39 (CDLI 41), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 40 (CDLI 223), circa 2100-2000; workers for carrying barley (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 41 (CDLI 164), circa 2100-2000; workers for the transport of spelt (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 42 (CDLI 302), circa 2100-2000; women taken into care (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 43 (CDLI 370), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 44 (CDLI 108), circa 2100-2000; delivery of wooden objects (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 45 (CDLI 271), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 46 (CDLI 290), circa 2100-2000; receipt for pickaxes (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 47 (CDLI 62), circa 2100-2000; receipt for sheep (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 48 (CDLI 83), circa 2100-2000; workers for the irrigation of fields (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 49 (CDLI 404), circa 2100-2000; delivery of cloths (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 50 (CDLI 85), circa 2100-2000; receipt for sheep (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 51 (CDLI 217), circa 2100-2000; receipt for wood and for reed mats as well as for a boat load of flour (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 52 (CDLI 372), circa 2100-2000; rations of barley (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 53 (CDLI 212), circa 2100-2000; plowmen [workers?] for the threshing of barley (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 54 (CDLI 162), circa 2100-2000; receipt for leather to hold utensils (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 55 (CDLI 218), circa 2100-2000; women for grinding grain (Box 3)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 56 (CDLI 198), circa 2100-2000; delivery of a reed mat (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 57 (CDLI 179), circa 2100-2000; receipt for dead animals (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 58 (CDLI 168), circa 2100-2000; receipt for glue for the temple door of Šulgi (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 59 (CDLI 13), circa 2100-2000; area of a plowed and harrowed field (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 60 (CDLI 326), circa 2100-2000; delivery of an donkey (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 61 (CDLI 324), circa 2100-2000; delivery of fish, birds, eggs, garlic (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 62 (CDLI 44), circa 2100-2000; receipt for wooden objects (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 63 (CDLI 110), circa 2100-2000; delivery of gras (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 64 (CDLI 381), circa 2100-2000; barley for the basket makers (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 65 (CDLI 134), circa 2100-2000; workers for erecting mill stones (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 66 (CDLI 245), circa 2100-2000; receipt for hides (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 67 (CDLI 473), circa 2100-2000; fields to be harvested (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 68 (CDLI 450), circa 2100-2000; delivery of oil (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 69 (CDLI 143), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reeds paid in barley (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 70 (CDLI 203), circa 2100-2000; levy of animals (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 71 (CDLI 89), circa 2100-2000; women for the transport of wheat (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 72 (CDLI 368), circa 2100-2000; receipt for barley for different persons (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 73 (CDLI 153), circa 2100-2000; ration of barley provided for Ur-Utu (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 74 (CDLI 399), circa 2100-2000; rations of wool (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 75 (CDLI 310), circa 2100-2000; receipt for two large containers (Box 4)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 76 (CDLI 178), circa 2100-2000; receipt for dead sheep (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 77 (CDLI 322), circa 2100-2000; levy of small livestock (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 78 (CDLI 45), circa 2100-2000; workers for towing a barley boat (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 79 (CDLI 283), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reed bundles (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 80 (CDLI 235), circa 2100-2000; workers for the tonde (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 81 (CDLI 389), circa 2100-2000; levy of barley (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 82 (CDLI 248), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 83 (CDLI 10), circa 2100-2000; workers for the transport of reed (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 84 (CDLI 228), circa 2100-2000; delivery of cloths (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 85 (CDLI 323), circa 2100-2000; a fat sheep for an offering (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 86 (CDLI 268), circa 2100-2000; receipt for hides (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 87 (CDLI 43), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reed bundles (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 88 (CDLI 145), circa 2100-2000; workers for cutting reeds (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 89 (CDLI 278), circa 2100-2000; levy of small livestock (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 90 (CDLI 222), circa 2100-2000; delivery of wooden objects (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 91 (CDLI 192), circa 2100-2000; receipt for baskets (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL92 (CDLI 250), circa 2100-2000; delivery of small livestock (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 93 (CDLI 46), circa 2100-2000; workers for hauling a boat loaded with dogwood ? (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 94 (CDLI 94), circa 2100-2000; delivery of a chest (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 95 (CDLI 289), circa 2100-2000; receipt for hides (Box 5)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 96 (CDLI 88), circa 2100-2000; delivery of baskets and mats (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 97 (CDLI 147), circa 2100-2000; workers charged with a flour transfer by boat (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 98 (CDLI 325), circa 2100-2000; delivery of a lamb, eggs, and garlic (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 99 (CDLI 63), circa 2100-2000; levy of animals (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 100 (CDLI 260), circa 2100-2000; delivery of wood (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 101 (CDLI 251), circa 2100-2000; workers for loading a boat for a kašdea (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 102 (CDLI 366), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 103 (CDLI 308), circa 2100-2000; pickaxe work (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 104 (CDLI 309), circa 2100-2000; rations of barley (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 105 (CDLI 266), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley rations for field workers (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 106 (CDLI 35), circa 2100-2000; receipt for pounded grain (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 107 (CDLI 57), circa 2100-2000; two men for storing barley and loading it on a boat (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 108 (CDLI 421), circa 2100-2000; money for dates (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 109 (CDLI 61), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reeds (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 110 (CDLI 187), circa 2100-2000; receipt for barley (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 111 (CDLI 405), circa 2100-2000; delivery of cloths (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 112 (CDLI 184), circa 2100-2000; receipt for two sheep (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 113 (CDLI 120), circa 2100-2000; workers overseeing a basin (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 114 (CDLI 169), circa 2100-2000; delivery of reed bundles to different feeders (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 115 (CDLI 181), circa 2100-2000; receipt for a dead goat (Box 6)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 116 (CDLI 453), circa 2100-2000; tag (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 117 (CDLI 220), circa 2100-2000; delivery of leather bags (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 118 (CDLI 104), circa 2100-2000; delivery of cut reeds (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 119 (CDLI 334), circa 2100-2000; delivery of small livestock (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 120 (CDLI 78), circa 2100-2000; women for erecting mill stones (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 121 (CDLI 77), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reed (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 122 (CDLI 80), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reed (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 123 (CDLI 262), circa 2100-2000; workers for working at a basin (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 124 (CDLI 95), circa 2100-2000; workers for loading, towing and unloading a boat (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 125 (CDLI 296), circa 2100-2000; delivery of containers (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 126 (CDLI 107), circa 2100-2000; delivery of reeds for the depot (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 127 (CDLI 34), circa 2100-2000; person hired for the pigpen (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 128 (CDLI 363), circa 2100-2000; barley ration for different persons (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 129 (CDLI 215), circa 2100-2000; delivery of nine vessels (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 130 (CDLI 304), circa 2100-2000; workers placed in marsa (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 131 (CDLI 306), circa 2100-2000; barley as a salary for hired men (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 132 (CDLI 387), circa 2100-2000; rations of barley (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 133 (CDLI 123), circa 2100-2000; workers for controlling the flow of the water (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 134 (CDLI 429), circa 2100-2000; delivery of containers (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 135 (CDLI 412), circa 2100-2000; silver and gold (Box 7)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 136 (CDLI 385), circa 2100-2000; rations of barley (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 137 (CDLI 390), circa 2100-2000; rations of barley (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 138 (CDLI 158), circa 2100-2000; barley to give out (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 139 (CDLI 170), circa 2100-2000; delivery of reed bundles to different feeders (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 140 (CDLI 36), circa 2100-2000; taking care of two menials (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 141 (CDLI 301), circa 2100-2000; workers for towing a boat to Ur (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 142 (CDLI 47), circa 2100-2000; workers for towing a barge (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 143 (CDLI 401), circa 2100-2000; delivery of cloths (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 144 (CDLI 219), circa 2100-2000; rations of barley (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 145 (CDLI 2), circa 2100-2000; workers sa-du8-ak gub-ba (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 146 (CDLI 24), circa 2100-2000; workers for works against canal erosion (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 147 (CDLI 172), circa 2100-2000; delivery of bundles of reed; workers for laying bricks (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 148 (CDLI 231), circa 2100-2000; reed bundles for the depot (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 149 (CDLI 8), circa 2100-2000; reeds for the reserve (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 150 (CDLI 303), circa 2100-2000; Women working on the bed of a canal (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 151 (CDLI 466), circa 2100-2000; wheat for delivery (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 152 (CDLI 295), circa 2100-2000; delivery of containers (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 153 (CDLI 7), circa 2100-2000; receipt for a basket and a reed mat (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 154 (CDLI 42), circa 2100-2000; women for the transport of reed (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 155 (CDLI 275), circa 2100-2000; harvest and harrow work (Box 8)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 156 (CDLI 118), circa 2100-2000; millers for erecting mill stones (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 157 (CDLI 208), circa 2100-2000; management of livestock (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 158 (CDLI 75), circa 2100-2000; irrigation works (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 159 (CDLI 27), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reed mats for the palace (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 160 (CDLI 298), circa 2100-2000; receipt for containers (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 161 (CDLI 148), circa 2100-2000; workers for the irrigation (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 162 (CDLI 171), circa 2100-2000; reed bundles for 2 feeders (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 163 (CDLI 100), circa 2100-2000; receipt for (palm) fibers (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 164 (CDLI 225), circa 2100-2000; workers for the depot (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 165 (CDLI 194), circa 2100-2000; workers for threshing (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 166 (CDLI 99), circa 2100-2000; receipt for sickles (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 167 (CDLI 150), circa 2100-2000; two sick workers (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 168 (CDLI 133), circa 2100-2000; receipt for wood (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 169 (CDLI 23), circa 2100-2000; canal excavation works (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 170 (CDLI 438), circa 2100-2000; workers for towing a boat to Umma (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 171 (CDLI 74), circa 2100-2000; workers for erecting mill stones (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 172 (CDLI 125), circa 2100-2000; workers for digging an irrigation channel (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 173 (CDLI 300), circa 2100-2000; workers for fieldwork (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 174 (CDLI 430), circa 2100-2000; delivery of reed mats (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 175 (CDLI 197), circa 2100-2000; receiving reeds (Box 9)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 176 (CDLI 256), circa 2100-2000; workers for towing a boat (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 177 (CDLI 236), circa 2100-2000; field work (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 178 (CDLI 105), circa 2100-2000; harvest and harrow work (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 179 (CDLI 291), circa 2100-2000; women for grinding and carrying barley (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 180 (CDLI 106), circa 2100-2000; harvest and harrow work (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 181 (CDLI 122), circa 2100-2000; workers for digging an irrigation channel (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 182 (CDLI 14), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation works (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 183 (CDLI 383), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 184 (CDLI 232), circa 2100-2000; women (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 185 (CDLI 55), circa 2100-2000; earthwork for a canal (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 186 (CDLI 441), circa 2100-2000; workers for transporting barley (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 187 (CDLI 270), circa 2100-2000; delivery of wooden objects (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 188 (CDLI 30), circa 2100-2000; receipt for reed mats (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 189 (CDLI 50), circa 2100-2000; receipt for baskets (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 190 (CDLI 124), circa 2100-2000; people for field work (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 191 (CDLI 9), circa 2100-2000; old reed mats (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 192 (CDLI 199), circa 2100-2000; delivery of hides (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 193 (CDLI 189), circa 2100-2000; delivery of nì-bàra (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 194 (CDLI 428), circa 2100-2000; containers (Box 10)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 195 (CDLI 396), circa 2100-2000; tax on date palms (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 196 (CDLI 320), circa 2100-2000; delivery of livestock (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 197 (CDLI 12), circa 2100-2000; four sheaths (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 198 (CDLI 418), circa 2100-2000; axes (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 199 (CDLI 157), circa 2100-2000; women for grinding grains for beer brewing (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 200 (CDLI 155), circa 2100-2000; workers for towing a boat loaded with barley (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 201 (CDLI 137), circa 2100-2000; delivery of barley for onagers (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 202 (CDLI 159), circa 2100-2000; receipt for leather (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 203 (CDLI 87), circa 2100-2000; women for the transport of flour (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 204 (CDLI 247), circa 2100-2000; women maintaining a basin (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 205 (CDLI 185), circa 2100-2000; hire of a person (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 206 (CDLI 103), circa 2100-2000; receipt for leather for plows (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 207 (CDLI 253), circa 2100-2000; women (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 208 (CDLI 140), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation work (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 209 (CDLI 6), circa 2100-2000; workers for transporting barley (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 210 (CDLI 252), circa 2100-2000; workers for different activities (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 211 (CDLI 200), circa 2100-2000; receipt for wood (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 212 (CDLI 101), circa 2100-2000; workers for the loading of objects (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 213 (CDLI 297), circa 2100-2000; women (Box 11)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 214 (CDLI 459), circa 2100-2000; earthwork (Box 12)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 215 (CDLI 20), circa 2100-2000; workers for irrigation works (Box 12)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 216 (CDLI 269), circa 2100-2000; women (Box 12)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 217 (CDLI 82), circa 2100-2000; workers for cutting reeds (Box 12)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 218 (CDLI 176), circa 2100-2000; delivery of baskets and reed mats (Box 12)
  - Cuneiform tablet SUL 219 (CDLI 376), circa 2100-2000; barley harvest from different fields (Box 12)